Mark Prince

7275 Ave Des Trembles. Laval, QC H7A0H2 | 514-831-5614 | markprince1999@gmail.com

Introduction

Hello, my name is Mark Prince. I am an Information Technology (IT) professional with experience with a large variety of platforms and environments, and I am looking for a full-time, part-time position or contract at ZNetworks, in either inside sales or Technical departments. I have many skills to contribute including Network and Server Management, Network installation & technical support, and website design & development. As a brief example, I have setup hybrid office + Cloud (AWS) server solutions to improve speed, reliability & security, solved various connectivity and speed issues and provided technical support for clients, all from my home office. My goal is to expand my IT knowledgebase and work with a company and position that I enjoy.

Professional Skills & Experience (10+ Years)

SERVER MANAGEMENT, DATA CENTER, NETWORKING

Office and Datacenter DELL Rackmount and Tower Servers. Ubiquity / Unify Managed Network Routers, Switches, and Access Points. LAN, WAN, VLAN, Unify Protect, Unify Access, Unify Talk, VPN, DNS, VoIP. DNS, DNS sinkholes and Recursive DNS. Website Hosting Service Deployment (Linux + Apache + MySQL/MariaDB, PHP), NodeJS. WebMin, WHM & cPanel, Virtual Machines. Bare Metal, Cloud and Hybrid Server Deployment, management & support. VM Ware EXSI Hypervisor, Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud. Microsoft Remote Desktop, VMWare Remote Console, VNC Server & Viewer. Operating Systems: CentOS, Ubuntu, Debian, Redhat, Windows, Raspbian. Also: Some experience with security penetration testing with tools such as Pentest and Kali Linux.

WEB & WEB APPLICATIONS

 Graphics using Photoshop, Coding in PHP, HTML5 / CSS3 using BBEDIT (Mac). Install, setup and deploy Web Servers running Linux + Apache + MariaDB/MySQL, and PHP). Some JavaScript, some NodeJS.
Google Analytics, SEMrush, Search Engine Optimization strategies, keyword optimization, code & image compression & optimization.

OPERATING SYSTEMS, SOFTWARE, LANGUAGES

 Apple Mac OS/X, Microsoft Windows Desktop & Server, Linux (CentOS, Redhat, Ubuntu, Kali, Raspbian), ESXI Hypervisor. SSH/Shell / Terminal, FTP, HTML5 / CSS3, Some PHP, MySQL/MariaDB, JavaScript & NodeJS. Terminal, Console. Zenmap, Webp Converter, Word, Excel, BBEdit, Photoshop, Parallels, Azure, PowerShell.

HARDWARE, INSTALLATION & DEPLOYMENT

· All Apple Mac's, All PC's, Dell Servers & Others, Bare Metal and Virtual Machines (VM's). Various managed & unmanaged Routers & Switches (especially Ubiquity / Unify), Wifi Access Points, Raspberry Pi.

MANAGEMENT & SALES

 Have managed teams of programmers, sales representatives, and employees to complete various projects on time. I also have a lot of previous sales experience in the software, hosting and technology fields including in-person trade show experience.

DIGITAL ARTIST

 Designer of various 2D & 3D Graphics for websites, signage, trade shows booths, magazine ads, banner advertising.

COMMUNICATION

• I have demonstrated software to small and large groups and was an invited speaker on several trade show panels. Trade Show representative. Systems Aggregation. Manager, negotiator.

Experience

IT CONSULTANT, SERVER & NETWORK MANAGEMENT. | INDEPENDANT | 2014-PRESENT

Leverage agile frameworks to provide a robust synopsis for high level overviews. Iterative approaches to corporate strategy foster collaborative thinking to further the overall value proposition. Linux and Windows Server Management, Network Optimization, Server-to-Cloud Migration, Website Design, Coding & Deployment, Web Server management & support, Software Development, Microsoft Azure, Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP, SSH, Video & Audio Streaming, Wowza, WebRTC, Ubiquity / Unify Networks, Wifi performance optimization, At-Home Network consulting, security improvements & technical support.

PRESIDENT | 2MUCH INTERNET SERVICES INC | 2001-2014

Web Applications, Server deployment Hosting Services, Technology integration, E-commerce integration, team management, problem solving and support. In-house server (30 servers (Linux)) installation & LAN Management plus 12 Workstations (Windows) Trade show, Graphics. Led special projects while ensuring they met strategic business requirements and were completed on time and within budget constraints. Managed 30 employees, monitored, and tracked resource capacity to support assignment, tracked progress through all testing phases, and completed work within budget. Provide on-going direction, coaching, Spearhead sales and marketing responsibilities, producing company image and marketing materials, managing website content, and propelling new business development. Integration of 3rd party solutions.

IT MANAGER | POWERCALL | 1997-2000

Managed all stages of application creations for clients, from initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and management of web sites. Performed software enhancement and tested newly implemented processes. Utilized extensive technical skills to develop client websites that exceeded expectations. Provided exceptional customer service while managing client emails in a timely manner. Provided efficient, cost-effective web hosting to exceed client's technical needs.

OWNER, SALES & TECHNICAL SPECIALIST | TMS COMPUTERS | 1987-1997

Provided planning, implementation and technical services for companies looking to connect their office networks to the Internet. Provided software and configuration solutions, new PC hardware and upgrades of existing hardware. Novell Network to Internet connectivity & device sharing. Analyzed effectiveness of system configuration and project requirements to enable appropriate changes based on existing business conditions and project growth. Clients included McGill University, Merck Frost, Au Bon Marche, MuchMusic, Musique Plus, Unidisc Music, RBI Compupak.

Education (Technology)

SELF TAUGHT.

I have always been a technology enthusiast and learned everything I know today on my own, or various online courses. I am currently training to get my CCNA (Certified Cisco Network Administrator) certificate, as well as AWS Cloud Practitioner & Data Analytics.

EDUCATION

Rosemount High School Vanier College, Concordia University.

Availability:

Am legal citizen of Canada, and have work authorization for Canada. Willing to relocate, work on premises or remote. Available anytime.